## CONTACT

+234 705 6427 599

johnikpeama96@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/john-ikpeama

Federal capital territory, Abuja, Nigeria

# **IKPEAMA** John Chiemeziem

Targeting Entry-Level Opportunity in...

Electrical/Electronics Engineering

Analytical-driven graduate in Electrical / Electronics Engineering with experience in power systems integration, generation, transmission, distribution, management and maintenance. Enthusiast in the tech space, programming & the digital world. Experienced in project managing, a team player who understands the importance of hard work, communication, dedication, time management, and co-operation.

# **EDUCATION**

First School Leaving Certificate (FSLC)

Mypa Schools, Minna, Niger state 2005 - 2010

Senior School Certificate Examination (NECO)

Federal Science and Technical College, Kuta-Shiroro, Niger State 2010 - 2016

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng)

Electrical/Electronics

Afe Babalola University, Ado-ekiti, Ekiti State

2017 - 2022

Post Graduate Diploma (PGDip)

Project Management
The Chartered Institute of Project Management, Ghana
2023

Graduate Diploma (GDip)

Health, Safety and Environment 1,2,3
The Chartered Institute of Environmental Health and Safety, state of Nevada, United States
2023

Diploma

Facility Management 2023

## **KEY SKILLS**

#### Hard skills

- Web developer (HTML, CSS & JavaScript)
- Microsoft office (Word, Excel & PowerPoint)
- · Altium designer & proteus PCB design suite
- · Graphics designer

#### Soft skills

- Communication
- · Time-management
- Leadership
- Adaptability
- Punctuality
- · Critical thinking

## LEADERSHIP ROLE

President - NYSC BAND CDS, Niger state
 May 2023 - October 2023

Corper's Liaison Officer (CLO) - NYSC BATCH C
 December 2022 - October 2023

## WORK EXPERIENCE

December 2022 - November 2023

National Examinations Council ICT Headquarters, Minna, Niger State

#### **Corps Member**

- · HVAC maintenance
- · Operation, repairs and inspections of lighting systems
- · Server maintenance
- · Computer maintenance (hardware & software)

March 2021 - August 2021

Transmission Company of Nigeria, Apo-Garki (132KV/33KV) substation, FCT, Abuja

#### **Engineering Intern**

- · Routine switch yard inspections & maintenance
- · Communication systems management
- Grounding & Installations of step-down transformers (33KV/132KV, 415V/11KV)
- · Operation & monitoring of the sub-station from the control room

September 2020 - October 2020

Afe Babalola University, Ado-Ekiti, Ekiti state

#### Student Intern

- Types and designs of HVAC systems used in buildings
- Electrical wiring types and installations process in buildings
- Visits to the school's substation and mini power plant demonstrating the step by step process in power generation, transmission and distribution

# **MEMBERSHIPS & CERTIFICATIONS**

Graduate Member, Nigerian Society of Engineers (NSE)

Associate of the Chartered Institute of Project Management (CIPM), Ghana

Member, the American Academy of Project Management (AAPM), United States

Member, the Chartered Institute of Contract Project and Facility Management (CICPFM)

Associate of the Chartered Institute of Environmental Health and Safety (CIEHS), Nevada, United States

## REFERENCE

Engr. Dr Sam Adebo

National Examination Council

Phone: +234 803 844 8079

Engr. Dr Femi Onibonoje

Afe Babalola University

Phone: +234 806 953 1521